from those who are here now can you tell
из того кто сейчас есть можешь сказать
what they say about the European Union what is
что они говорят про Евросоюз что там
difficult
сложного
bad about the European Union but about the European Union to be
плохого про Евросоюз но про Евросоюз
honest I feel a little
честно говоря Евросоюз мне немножко
sorry for the European Union because if now
жалко жалко потому что если сейчас
Ukraine has
Украина с
closed all its doors with gas then this
газом закрыла все свои двери то в этом
year the European Union will still call I don't
году-то ещё Евросоюз вызовет вот я не
know what will happen next year
знаю как будет в следующем году
how much gas will rise maybe
насколько газ поднимется может быть
again it will be at a thousand it has
опять же будет по тысяче он и так
already risen somewhere by 20 but
поднялся уже где-то пров на 20 но
maybe more Will rise next year
возможно ещё Поднимется на следующий год
how will gas be bought in euros I
как будет газ в евро покупать я вот
honestly don't
честно говоря не
know
знаю
Hello, I understand you are from Poland
Здравствуйте вы так я понимаю из Польши
Yes you are quite insightful What are you
Да вы довольно проницательный О чём
talking about here you are really uh not thinking that
общаетесь тут вы исти ээ не думая что у
you don't notice like a flag on your
вас не замет как бы флаг на вашем
background that well you can just see your background so it's
фоне что ну просто видно ваш фон поэтому
not very difficult to guess Well you are a
догадаться не очень сложно Ну Вы
wonderful person you notice
замечательные довольно человек замечаете
and that's all And what are you talking about
и всё А чём общаетесь
I am interested in honestly three
Меня интересует честно говоря три
questions let's start with the first if you
вопроса начнём с первого если вы
allow Let's have
позволите Давайте
yours from Poland The most important person
тут ваш из Польши Самый главный человек
said that most
сказал что скорее
likely in the near future we will have to lead
всего ближайшем будущем придётся вести
troops to Ukraine Yes of the European Union to Ukraine
войска в Украину Да Евросоюза на Украину
Yes  but this is literally news for a long time Yes
Да но это буквально новость доль Да
today we finally applauded that we
сегодня мы наконец-то аплодировали что
finally matured
наконец-то созрели
Yes and you with what will
Да и вы с что
lead to something good Well of course
к чему-то хорошему приведёт Ну конечно
the more troops will fight against Russia the
чем больше войск против России будет
faster Russia will have a
воевать тем России быстрее будет
beard Maybe you are right but don't you
борода Возможно вы правы но как бы не
think that at the same time the
думаете что в это время же
troops from Europe including Poland
войска с Европы в том числе и с Польше
can even die a little Well yes
могут и чуть-чуть
And what is this
умирать Ну да И что это
war for you at all Russians die or not
война вам вообще умират россияне или нет
Here we want the faster this war to
Вот мы хотим чтобы чем быстрее эта война
end Wait well here is the goal goal goal
закончи Подождите ну вот цель цель цель
because of what we will say yours may not be
из-за чего скажем ваши может быть не
brothers Yes but maybe some acquaintances
братья Да но может быть знакомые
will simply clean up for which I will
какие-то просто будут убирать за что
explain Yes it's just their job we have a
объясню Да это просто ихняя работа у нас
contract army in Poland Yes the people
контрактная армия в Польше Да вот люди
who sign the contract they go
которые подписывают контракт они идут
this is their job you understand that is they
это ихняя работа понимаете то есть они
kill Russian occupiers Well damn it's
убивают оккупантов российских Ну блин
just business they choose it themselves no
просто бизнес они сами выбирают это их
one forces them Donald said something
никто не заставляет Дональд ту сказал
like yes We need better we will kill
типа да Нам нужно лучше мы будем убивать
occupiers somewhere there on the border of Russia
оккупантов где-то там на границе России
and Ukraine yes than we will have to do it
и Украины да чем нам придётся это делать
on the border of Russia and
на границе России и
Poland I
Польше У меня
just don't know dissonance  some in my
просто не знаю диссонанс какой-то в
head
голове
now Excuse me for
сейчас Извини
a second
секундочку
here is how Russia is on
вот ведь как бы Россия на
Poland Despite the fact that you there
Польшу Несмотря на то что вы там Всё
We supply everything on the land for everything on the
поставляет мы на землю на всё на
state on yours we do not comprehend in any way And
государство на вашу никак не постигаем А
you say so openly that
вы так открыто говорите
you need us as if
что вам надо нас как бы
a little because yes Moscow is
немножко потому что да Москва это это
Polish
польские
territories You remember When there was troubles
территории Вы помните Когда было смута
Yes when the Polish Tsarevich was supposed to
Да когда польский Царевич должен был
ascend the throne and the boyars elected Yes you have
войти на трон и избрали бояре да у вас
Minin and Pozharsky made an
Минин и Пожарский сделали бунт
illegal rebellion and overthrew the legitimate king
незаконный и свергли законного короля
This is Moscow this belongs to
это Москва это принадлежит
Poland We We are returning our
Польше Мы Мы возвращаем своё
those times then I will allow myself to also show
те времена то я позволю себе тоже
off a little knowledge half of
немножко блеснуть знаниями половина
Poland was under Russian princes This was
Польши была под русскими князями Это уже
later This was later after after
потом это уже потом после после того как
you took and illegally overthrew our tsar
вы взяли и незаконно свергли нашего царя
that's
вот и
all And now we are by right of the strong
всё И сейчас мы по праву сильного
Look the thing is that yes When Russia the
Смотрите дело в том что да Когда Россия
Russian Empire was strong when the
Российская империя была сильная когда
Soviet Union was strong now Russia is
Советский Союз был сильный сейчас Россия
weak we can come and take what is
слаба мы можем прийти и забрать то что
rightfully ours and that's it
лежит нам по праву и
But you remember that in the Senate year
всё но вы же помните что в сенатом году
Russia was the weakest No it was not the
Россия была самая слабая Нет она не была
weakest then it literally went to pieces
самая слабая тогда буквально разошлось
completely so look so Poland Poland did
полностью так смотри так Польша Польше
not exist at all in the seventeenth year it
вообще не было в семнадцатом году она
only after the destruction of Russia began to
только после разрушения России начала
gather from Austria it was torn
собираться из Австрии она была разорвана
between different states it was just
между разными государствами она только
born then everything And now we are strong
родилась тогда всё А сейчас мы силь
now we have a NATO group in Europe the
сейчас у нас группировка НАТО в Европе
largest in Poland Yes deployed
наибольшее в Польше Да развёрнутые
brigades ready to slap the Kaliningrad
бригады готовые хлопнуть калининградскую
region in 2-3 hours yes that is completely
область за 2-3 часа да то есть полностью
in the Baltic Sea already Finns Estonians
в Балтийском море уже фины эстонцы
Danes are already blockading
датчане уже делают блокаду кораблей
Russian ships first played with tankers
российских сначала поиграли на танкерах
Now everything that is Kaliningrad it has 2
Теперь всё то есть Калининград ему 2-т
hours to live in a military clash Yes
часа при военном столкновении жить Да
further
дальше
Yes excuse me but now let's say with
Да извините но у нас сейчас скажем с
Ukraine when the War is going on you see
Украиной когда Война идёт вы же видите
Yes how this War is going very very very
Да как эта Война идёт очень очень очень
slowly even the Second World War
медленно даже Вторая мировая война уже
would have already ended How is our
закончилась бы Как идёт вот наше это
confrontation going because the war IT is no longer
противостояние потому что война ИТ уже
on different
по другим
principles the attack is not being abandoned the War of
принципам атаку не бросает идёт Война
technologies is going on and that is why you say that
технологий и поэтому вы так говорите что
immediately but what if suddenly for example
сразу вот а если вдруг к примеру
all of Europe decided to send troops and
вся Европа решила войска вести и у нас
Plan B works for us that is to hit where the
срабатывает План Б то есть бить туда где
headquarters are against us as if defense that is
штабы противо нас как бы оборон то есть
They will take and drop more
Они возьмут и скинут более там Более
serious warheads on countries that are in
серьёзные боеголовки на страны которые в
our opposition, it is not scary, look, on the
нашем противо это не страшно смотрите на
territory of Poland, on the border, there is the
территории Польши на границе стоит
US Seventh Army, the US Seventh Army,
Седьмая армия США Ракетная Седьмая армия
deployed towards Moscow and
США развёрнутая в сторону Москвы и
Leningrad, that's all, that's why, uh, 12,000
Ленинграда вот и всё Поэтому ээ 12.000
people, missiles, a missile umbrella, a missile
человек ракет ракетный зонтик ракетный
umbrella, I explain, 12,000 people, that is such a
зонтик я объясняю 12.000 человек это
big army, yes, missiles, that is such a
такая большая армия Да ракет это такая
big army, yes, even more so, look, well, yes,
большая армия да тем более смотри Ну да
there are technologies, I agree, but 12
там Технологии есть согласен но 12
people, that is, I will explain, on our
человек этон я объясню у нас по
TV in Poland, yes, on our TV in Poland, they
телевизору в Польше Да у нас по
show,
телевизору в Польше показывают у нас
at first, they said that it is impossible to
сначала ээ говорили что нельзя
send
отправлять ээ
troops to destroy the Russian
войска на уничтожение российских
occupiers because Russia can
оккупантов потому что Россия может
somehow react harshly, but
как-то отреагировать жёстко Но после
after Ukraine captured part of the Kursk
того как Украина захватила часть Курской
region, liberated it and Russia
области освободила и Россия ничего не
can do nothing, all our cards are
может сделать Всё у нас все карты
open and Donald Tusk, today, his
открыты и Дональд Туск он сегодня его
speech on Telegram channels, only part of him was
речь в Telegram каналах только часть его
pushed, he said in Polish,
толкали у нас на польском языке он
that, look, Russia is
говорил это что вот смотрите Россия
weaker than ever, it  cannot win back
слаба как никогда она не может отвоевать
some district center in the Kursk region,
какой-то райцентр в Курской области
therefore we must use
поэтому мы должны использовать
Russia's weakness to the maximum to
максимально слабость России для
deal it a deadly blow while
нанесения ей смертоносного удара пока
all
все войска
its troops are tied up in Ukraine, we
её находятся в связаны в Украине мы
must
должны
strike Leningrad,
ударить с Балтийского моря по ленинграду
Pskov and Moscow from the Baltic Sea and you will delay all this,
Пскову и на Москву и всё это
wait, what am I
оттянешь подожди что я рассказ
telling you, look, Ukraine strikes
рассказываю смотри Украина наносит удар
like Crimea, cutting it off immediately, yes, Crimea
типа по Крыму отрезая его сразу да Крым
falls,
падает
brother, so to Russia,
брат так России
True, he is both brother and not brother, naturally,
Правда он и брат и не брат естественно
you are right, this is all politics, yes,
Вы правы это всё политика да Он из
Erdogan drove Russia out of Turkey, and
Турции эрдоган выбил Россию да и задача
Erdogan's task is also to drive Russia out of the Black Sea,
эрдогана тоже да с Чёрного моря выбить
that is, Erdogan wants the
Россию то есть эрдоган хочет чтобы на
only Maritime power left on the Black Sea to
Чёрном море осталась единственная
do, turn off the pipes
Морская держава сделать отключать трубы
immediately, literally, they will immediately disconnect him from the pipe from
сразу буквально его сразу от трубы
our pipe, they will
отключат от нашей трубы
disconnect him from the pipe, what is going on our
труб его отключат пото Что идёт по нашим
T-wire, so Azerbaijan, on the contrary, with
Т проводу так Азербайджан наоборот с
Turkey, Azerbaijan against Russia
Турцией Азербайджан против России
Now it is correct, but we have a joint
Сейчас правильно но у нас совместное
venture, the pipes are ours, so they are trumpeting,
предприятие трубы то наши поэтому трубят
As is, Turkey is left without gas at all,
Как как есть Турция остаётся вообще без
so no, look, look, Turkey Now
поэтому нет смотри смотри Турция Сейчас
Yes, after they drove Russia out of
Да после того как выгнали Россию из
Syria now  gas will be pumped from a
Сирии сейчас газ будут прокачивать из
boat to Europe through Syria and Turkey By the
катера в Европу через Сирию и Турцию Вот
way The only thing you can
кстати Единственное что что ты можешь
say that is true I am also in shock Turkey
сказать это правда я тоже в шоке Турцию
Sorry
Извини
please Russia was kicked out of Syria and
пожалуйста Россию из Сирии выгнали и вот
I don't know this What do you think the
это вот я не знаю ты как считаешь потреб
Syrians need to hand over Erdogan What do you
сирийцы выдать эрдогана что как ты
think not Erdogan but
думаеш не эрдогана а
this
этого
Assad here in front of
асада ту
all these Nazi bandits
пере всех этих бандитов нацистов
Yanukovych Assad they he does not hand over so p
Януковича асада они он не выдаёт так п
Nazi bandits let's do without it
бандитов нацистов давай без этого
Yanukovych he was not he is white fluffy
Янукович он не было он белый пушистый по
compared to the same Zelensky he has
сравнению с тем же Зеленским он ни одну
not unleashed a single war and has not killed so many people that is not the point the point is that they
войну не развязал и столько людей не
made a
сделали
political statement we will leave
политические заявление мы оставим базы
Syrian bases in Russia If you take Assad and I
Сирии в России Если вым вы асада и вот я
also think
тоже думаю
that a politician will agree to, as it were, on the
что на политика согласится как бы с
one hand, hand over in front of the entire world
одной стороны придать при всей мировой
community his former ally on the
общественности своего бывшего союзника с
other hand, keep the bases in Syria
другой стороны баз сохранить в Сирии вот
I am also in shock I don't know this is like
Я вот тоже в шоке вот не знаю это же как
e
бы е
Shahman back and forth plush and everything you will lose the
Шахман туда-сюда плюш и всё проиграешь
bases if you hand over  Assad they demanded to
базы если выдать асада они потребовали
hand over Assad and pay for the destruction of
выдать асада и выплатить за разрушение
Syrian cities And then they will think
сирийских городов А тогда они подумают
only like this they
только вот так они
said Well, probably we have different
сказали Ну наверное у нас как бы разные
sources if Well, you agree, look, Erdogan is behind
источники иф Ну вы согласны смотрите за
Syria, Erdogan is behind the new authorities of
сирией стоит эрдоган за новыми властями
Syria and Erdogan
Сирии стоит эрдоган и эрдогану в
absolutely does not need a Russian base in the Mediterranean,
Средиземном море русская база абсолютно
agree, the
не нужна согласитесь
truth is you know how, like you and
правда в этом знаешь как как и вы как и
I, we dont
я мало
understand much, it seems, not particularly,
разбираемся кажется особо нет
but it seems to us that we
но это нам кажется что мы нормально
understand normally, after all, we are not
разбираемся всё-таки мы не
professionals, what do you have a
профессионалы что у вас
cough Sorry, Im a little sick, cough, what
кашлем Извините немножко болею каш что
What are you sick with,
Чем
snot, at school, our daughters have
болеете сопли у нас в школе дочки уже
not been studying for a week because
неделю как бы не учимся потому что как
everyone is sick since the quarantine, something, thats
карантин все болеют что-то вот
a little bit wrong, okay, thats not the
немножко это неверн да ладно не в этом
point, but the snot is green, exactly,
дело а сопли зелёные именно
yes, yes, but its a little painful,
да ну да но забит немножко болезненно
green snot, clogged, yes, for now, for now, you will
зелёный сопли Да вот пока пока будете
think badly of Zelensky Until then, there
плохо думать о зеленском Пока да тех пор
will be green snot, thats it Well, do you
будет зелёные сопли это такое Ну а вы
think that he is a good president, thats
считаете что он хороший президент вот
really it  even just
реально вот даже вот вот
imagine that it was not
чисто если представить что это была не
Ukraine but Poland when Zelensky gives
Украина а Польша когда Зеленский даёт
consent for its subsoil Well, you yourself would have
Согласие о своих недрах Ну вы бы сами
agreed to
согласились
pay off
отдавать
debts with your subsoil Well, I do
долги своими недрами Ну это
nt know
же не знаю вряд
why you Russians Yes, it does matter
почему вам россиянам Да есть дело до
what kind of President there is in
того какой там Президент в
Ukraine And you know, up until what year I was
Украине А знаешь мне до чего года я
rarely interested in it, but once I
вообще редко интересовался но один раз я
looked somewhere In the fifteenth year I
посмотрел где-то В пятнадцатом году я я
started to be interested in Ukraine and it
начал интересоваться Украиной и
turned out
оказалось
that in 2015
что года
Ukraine was developing
Украина в год развивалась
8% per year, that is, it was raising the GDP quite a bit
8% то есть на во довольно ВП
under Prime Minister Azarov Yes, he was
поднимала при премьере азарове Да он был
Prime Minister, but there was Yanukovych, but the Prime Minister was
премьером но был Янукович но премер был
Azarov and I dont really respect Yanukovych
Азаров и вот Януковича я не очень уважаю
as a person, he is a weakling as a president and
как человека он как президент Слабак и
everything else ran away Well, the latter,
всё остальное убежал это Ну последни ещё
probably, about the golden toilet, I even
наверное насчёт золотого унитаза я даже
believe there are some like that
верю есть такие вот такие
who I dont want Okay, thats all But Azarov
которые не хочу Ладно всё А вот Азаров
As an example, I really respect his intelligence and he
Как пример его ум я реально уважаю он и
gave specific data He agreed to
и конкретные данные давал Он согласился
integration with Europe only
на интеграцию с Европой только в том
if Europe
случае если Европа
makes a discount to give
э сделает скидку на то чтобы дать время
Ukraine time to become European-standard production
производством Украины стать на стандарты
Europe  I didn't agree Well, it's
Европы Европа не соглашалась Ну там
very difficult there now if it's all
очень тяже сейчас если это всё
pretty hard to deploy
развёртывать довольно-таки тяжело
really Azarov fell behind the interests of Ukraine
реально Азаров отстал интересы Украины
turned out to me as an example of a very interesting
оказался как примером очень интересный
person and after
человек а после
him in Ukraine really well complete chaos
него реально на Украине ну бардак полный
Well, here is inflation and everything else I
Ну вот и инфляция и всё остальное мне
just feel sorry for the residents of Ukraine really feel
просто жалко жителей Украины реально
sorry for ordinary residents of Ukraine and
жалко простые жите Украины и
in general for
вообще во
each other They kill I don't know when it
друг друга Убивают не знаю когда это
will end Listen, here's such an interesting
закончится Слушай а вот такой интересный
question Do you feel sorry for the residents of Ukraine what about
вопрос Тебе жалко жителей Украины что
Azarov you know all this
там Азаров ты всё это знаешь
And what about your dentistry why don't you
А что у тебя со стоматологией почему вот
worry about your teeth I'm
ты не переживаешь про свои зубы Вот мне
interested yes but you worry you know
интересно да но переживаешь ты знаешь
that Azarov has been there since 2014
что там с четырнадцатого года Азаров там
You are still worried about Ukraine Why is it so
всё Ты всё переживаешь за Украину Почему
bad for them to live as Ukrainians
так вот плохо им живётся украинцем
now without Azarov but you don't worry about
теперь без Азарова но не переживаешь за
your dentistry Why
свою стоматологию Почему
Well, if the truth be told I'm telling you I have
Ну если по правде Я же тебе говорю у
four children
меня вот четверо детей
Well, right now I'm in my
Да вот сейчас в квартире нахожусь своей
wife's apartment and I had a little fight with her I
жены вот я с не немножко разругался у
have another apartment with a room
меня ещё одна квартира есть комнатная
a little further I usually live there
немножко дальше я обычно сейчас там живу
now sometimes I come here and it turns out
сейчас иногда сюда прихожу и получается
that I  all the money is pensions Yes VS that's it
так что я все деньги пенсии Да ВС вот
and your own money earnings
это вот и свои деньги заработок
like everything for children Especially since I say
как всё на детей Тем более у меня говорю
younger these are 4 years old girls
младше это 4 года девочки
here Three daughters one son Well, the son is already
вот Три дочки один сын Да ну сын-то уже
at university But Three daughters they are still
в университете А вот Три дочки они ещё
small on
маленькие на
themselves here they also broke my jaw in a fight and my
себя тут мне ещё в драке челю сломали
teeth are rotting it
ите зубы гниют
turns out no matter what they are from
получается независимо от чего они у меня
all my nerves are
все нервы-то
damaged And I think there is a sute
повреждены И я думаю сть сют
Well too much money is needed
Ну слишком много денег надо
understand 49 years old Well soon it will be 50 And
понима 49 лет Ну скоро 50 будет А
how much money is needed to do all this Wow, we
сколько денег надо чтобы это всё сделать
have about
Ух ты у нас на зуб где-то примерно
35,000 per tooth can you imagine all 350 dollars per
35.000 представляешь все 350 долларов на
tooth yes Well, yes, that's about it Well
зуб да Ну да примерно так получается Ну
listen But I have daughters they have been with me for the
слушай У меня зато дочки они у меня уже
third year now every Sunday two daughters
третий год каждое воскресение две дочки
they
они на лошадях
ride horses they They really
катаются они Вот реально на лошадях
ride horses at the
катаются на
hippodrome plus they do gymnastics and
ипподроме плюс гимнастикой занимаются
dance that is everything is fine Well everything is for the
танцами то есть всё нормально Ну всё для
children But you are right about this Yes, it has been like that for a long time No,
детей А вот с этим ты прав да давне на
I just don't understand look
выду так Нет просто я не понимаю смотри
Russia has oil gas gold diamonds  the
Россия имеет нефть газ золото алмазы
richest country And all the people have
богатейшая страна А у всех людей
problems with dentistry Why do
проблемы со стоматологией Почему
Americans have three children too,
американцы у них тоже есть трое детей
four children, but their teeth are normal, and their
четверо детей но зубы нормальные и
cars and military and their apartments are normal Houses,
машины и ВС и квартиры нормальные Дома
yes But the Russians, but the Russians are worried about
да А вот россияне но россияне переживают
Azarov Damn, you asked philosophical
Азарова Блин ну ты задал философские
questions
вопросы
Why, why is it good to live in Rus' As the
почему почему на Руси жить хорошо Как
classics wrote Well,
написали классики Ну
why does someone have more money,
почему кому-то у кого-то больше дене
someone has less
кого-то меньше
money,
денег
lie By the way, I have a brother Yes, he lives in Moscow,
ври Кстати у меня вот брат Да в Москве
works at TNT, his salary is
живёт работает на ТНТ у него зарплата
more than 400 thousand a
400 с лишним тысяч в
month, but I'm ashamed To ask him for money
месяц но мне стыдно У него денег
because he is the younger brother,
попросить потому что он младший брат
somehow, damn, no Well, yes, you don't
как-то вот блин вот не Ну да просить не
need to ask, question, question, no Why ca
надо вопрос вопрос не Почему просить
n't you get your
вопрос Почему вы в России не можете
teeth done in Russia Well, how can Russia have a
сделать себе зубы Ну как Россия имеет
huge
огромнейшее
amount of money, yes it Look, I'm
количество денег да она Смотри я
a bit of a person That's so simple for
немножко человек-то Вот такой простой
me, right, for me, for myself, I've
мне вот прямо мне ль на себя вот я вот
probably let myself go
сам наверное себя запустил в последнее
lately, and wait a second so that you
время и подожди секундочку чтоб ты
understand Look, look, you see
больше Понял Вот посмотри Да вот видишь
what kind of
какая это
crap this is Hey, turn on the camera, yeah  yeah yeah yeah yeah I don't
фигня Эй Включи камеру дада дадада да не
know I've
знаю я жирный
become fat And so I just let's say this
стал И вот я только вот скажем этой
fall this fall I took myself in hand I gave
осенью этой осенью что-то за себя взялся
up on myself so I
что-то на себя так плюнул поэтому себя
took myself in hand I lost 7 kg and I'm trying to
взялся я похудел на 7 кг и пытаюсь у
lose weight further because it's become hard
дальше похудеть потому что стало тяжело
even to walk It's okay
вообще даже ходить тяжело
I think I'll
стало Да ничего я думаю за годик ещё
lose another 30 kilograms in a year I hope so And
килограмм 30 сброшу Это я надеюсь А
how much do you weigh now
сколько ты сейчас весишь
122 Well yeah And height Well, you're
122 Ну да А рост Да вообще
175 I understand And you sit on chat roulette and
175 понял а в чатрулетке сидишь с
communicate with Ukrainians yeah And you know uh
украинцами общаешься да А знаешь
I
э я себе
used to tell myself uh that I shouldn't communicate
ээ раньше говорил что не надо общаться
Because when I communicated with Ukrainians there was
потому что когда общался с украинцами в
mostly a lot of negativity But somehow
основном очень много негатива но как-то
I managed to
у меня получалось среди большего
meet very good people among the most negativity
негатива встречать очень хороших людей
Yeah And we communicated well with them I felt like
Угу И мы с ними хорошо общались мне
I thought so Yes maybe there will be
стало мне я так подумал Да может быть
20 people who will tell
будет человек 20 которые будут посылать
you to go to hell But with someone you're so you It
тея куда подальше но с кем-то ты се ты
turns out you're supporting the war
получается ты ты поддерживаешь войну
against
против
Ukraine You haven't heard me The radio What kind of
Украины ты меня радио не слышал какую
war am I supporting against
войну поддерживаю против
Ukraine I'm talking about the fact
Украины именно говорю о том
that this whole situation The whole situation
что вся эта ситуация вся ситуация
only happened because
произошла только из
You know history  our Russia yes, yes, yes, yes, they
вот ты же знаешь историю нашей России да
themselves bombed their own, their own
де года да сами бомбили свой это свой
parliament Yes, and then all these
парламент Да а потом все эти девяностые
nineties we all voted for
года мы все голосовали За то чтобы нас
these, our people, to rob us, all the
эти вот наш народ нас всё грабили все
factories, everything, destroy everything, everything, Herod,
заводы всё разрушали всё Ирод
and for democracy, damn, the country was literally
и за демократию блин страна буквально
dying, and now I look at Ukraine and it
умирала и вот я смотрю на Украину и мне
seems to me that the same thing is happening, it seems like they
кажется происходит тоже самое вроде как
want to strive for a bright future,
бы хотят к светлому будущему крана
but in the end it is still a
стремиться но в результате это это всё
promise And what will happen as a result?
обещание А что же получится в результате
Well, in fact, they are unlikely to join the European Union
Ну на самом деле в Евросоюз вряд ли
But even if they join, they will again
вступят Но даже если вступят опять же
demand from us, from Russians, that they be,
потребуют как с нас с россиян чтобы были
like, the same, according to the same laws, according to the same
вот как бы те же по тем же законам по
standards They are
тем же стандартам
predators,
Они же они же хищники
they plundered Africa, what is wrong with the
они Африку разграбили что плохо в
standards of the European Union, what
стандартах Евросоюза какие там
standards are there, there is nothing bad, we just
стандарты ничего плохого просто мы не
cannot reach them yet. And for example,
можем пока до них достичь А например
what standards that we cannot reach,
Какие стандарты что мы не можем дости
that you cannot reach,
что вы не можете достичь
you are
вы
now okay, okay, that's right, first of all,
сечас хорошо ладно сес точно во-первых
what I heard about chicken, in order to sell
что я слышал курица чтобы продавать
chicken, you
курятину
need certain GOSTs for vaccinations,
нужно определённые ГОСТы по прививкам
eh, how to keep chickens That
э как содержа Как содержать курицы То
is,  all this should be described
есть это всё должно быть описано
shown Not just buy from people But
показано Не просто скупить у людей А вот
exactly everything should be
именно всё должно быть
legally there everything is formalized then they
э юридическо там всё оформлено то тогда
can sell the question all the meat
могут продавать вопрос все то мясо
that you buy in Russia in
которое вы покупаете в России в
supermarkets what do you think it is grandmothers who
супермаркетах вы что думаете Это бабушки
raise chickens these are birds farms
курей выращивают это птиц фермы
naturally no Yes everything is farms You are right that so that
естественно нет Да всё ца фермы Вы правы
is look the European Union
то что так то есть смотри Евросоюз
makes GOST so that people are fed
делает ГОСТ чтобы людей кормили
normal food and not some
нормальной едой а не какой-то там
salmonella crap
сальмонеллой фигнёй
No no we don't have that either For
Да нет у нас же ведь тоже не Вот вы к
example you are in the European Union there they don't really sell sour cream
примеру в Евросоюзе там и сметана особо
there and with kefir
там и с кефиром
Well we literally sell it in bags but
Ну мы буквально в пакетах его продаём а
there you can't buy it like that these are yogurts it turns out there is a
там так не получится купить это йогурты
certain packaging
получается определённая упаковка
everywhere again Look E once come on come on
везде ещё раз Смотри Е раз давай давай
you I just can't understand what the
давай ты Я просто не могу понять в чём
problem is for example if what are the standards of the
проблема например если Какие стандарты
European Union are not achievable for Russia
Евросоюза Не достижимы для России
for example
например
[music] please don't
[музыка]
drive me into a corner these are
ты не загоняй пожалуйста в угол это
rather complex questions that are beyond my
вопросы довольно-таки сложные не по моей
competence But I can explain only
компетенции Но я могу объяснить только
one thing I listen to competent people
одним я слушаю компетентных людей
who are talking about exactly this  they said they
которые именно об этом говорили они
said with examples I can also maybe
говорили примерами Я тоже мож могу тоже
explain these examples but not specifically
эти примерами объяснить но не конкретно
why this is happening yes explain these
почему так происходит да объясни эти
examples explain these examples I'm
примеры объясни эти примеры мне
interested Well, you
интересно
know Sorry, but to be honest,
ж знаешь Извини но сейчас честно
nothing really comes to mind right now I don't
говоря в голову-то особо ничего не
think that I'll say
приходит не думаю что я вот скажем
at all well, just nothing comes to mind right now
совсем ну просто ничего в голову сейчас
Maybe you can tell me I don't know
не приходит Может быть ты подскажешь я
I don't know what the
не знаю я не знаю какие в этом в
standards are in this European Union that they are terrible for
Евросоюзе стандарты что они страшные для
or
или
Ukraine No, that's not how I raised the question I
Украины Нет я же не так вопрос поднял Я
raised the question that the standards are not bad It's
вопрос поднял что стандарты они неплохие
just that I listened to Azarov when he
Просто я ви я слушал Азарова когда он
said that in order to switch to the standards of the
говорил что чтобы перейти на стандарты
European Union we need about 80
Евросоюза нам нужно порядка 80
billion which if the European Union allocates it
миллиардов которые если выделит Евросоюз
will be
будет
good
хоро ска
change e where
изм э де
your standards need a lot of
ваши нужно очень много
money Paul, look at Azarov Azarov has been gone for
денег Поль смотри Азаров Азарова уже нет
But from this it is not worth saying that he was
Но из этого не стоит говорить что он был
wrong he was exactly for just like that
неправ он же как раз и за как раз это
happened before the revolution of dignity
происходило перед революцией гидности
when
когда
he when he signed the documents
он когда он подписывал документы
let's have someone Azarov has been gone for a long time, in
давай кого-то азаро уже давно нет он
my opinion he has already died in short even yes like
по-моему уже короче умер даже да типа
twice like Sanya
два раза как Саня
about here
про вот кого-то из того кто сейчас есть
can you tell me who is here now what they say about the
можешь сказать что они говорят про
European Union what is so difficult and
Евросоюз что там сложного
bad about the European Union but
плохого про Евросоюз но про Евросоюз
honestly speaking I feel a little
честно говоря Евросоюз мне немножко
sorry for Zhakov because if now
жакова жалко потому что если сейчас
Ukraine with gas
Украина с газом
[music] has
[музыка]
closed all its doors then this year the
закрыла все свои двери то в этом году-то
European Union will still call I dont know how it will be
ещ Евросоюз вызовет вот я не знаю как
next year how much gas will
будет в следующем году на сколько газ
rise maybe it will be again at a
поднимется может быть опять же будет по
thousand it has already risen somewhere around
тысяче он и так поднялся уже где-то про
20 but its possible it will rise
на 20 но возможно ещё Поднимется на
next year how will they buy gas I
следующий год как будет газ покупать я
honestly dont know if
вот честно говоря не знаю если вот
Ukraine or there is a development of my doubts Im
укра или там развите мои сомнения я не с
laughing for the wrong reason Im laughing because you, a man from
того смеюсь я смеюсь что вы мужик из
Russia who cant
России который не может
afford to restore
себе позволить реставрировать
his face, are worried about how the poor
фейс переживает о том как бедный
European Union will survive the next winter without
Евросоюз выживет следующую зиму без газа
Russian gas Yes by the way, yes, these are not my
российского Да кстати да не мои
worries no no Im not worried Im thinking that because
переживания не не я не переживаю Я думаю
of this most likely the
о том что из-за этого скорее всего
time will come when the European Union will
возможно наступит время когда Евросоюз
suddenly think that And maybe it does
Вдруг подумает что А может быть с
nt put up with Russia  So, how to
Россией не ставит Так вот как бы
conflict Maybe we should be friends I
конфликтовать Может стоит дружить я из
am blowing from this topic Listen, what are the
из этой тематики дую Слушайте а какие
problems Japan has now because of this war, more
проблемы
specifically, a little bit, I am not talking about the
сейчас конкретнее немножко я не по
problem with gas And what is the problem in Japan now
проблема с газом А в Японии сейчас какая
Great, Japan is at the
проблема Здорово в Японии в данный
moment But they still havent recovered
момент Но они до сих пор ещё не отошли
from the
от
crisis,
кризиса
their banking is mainly
банкирский у них Обит в основном
technology and now, well, thats the most
технологии и сейчас ну это максимум что
I know about Japan, to be honest,
я знаю про Японию честно
their banks are in
говоря банки у них там пока в
crisis, technology is slipping away a little, but
кризисе технологии чуть-чуть уплывают но
they are still
они пока хорошо ещё
holding up well Toyota is still a good
держатся Toyota до сих пор хорошая
car Thats why its sold all over the world
машина Вот и продаётся по всему миру
and I dont know what will happen next, but
и не знаю как дальше будет но уже
unfortunately, no one buys phones and TVs from Japan,
телефоны к сожалению и телевизоры из
that is, Japan is
Японии никто не покупает то есть Япония
rotting, in principle, you can say its
загнивает в принципе можно так сказать
problematic
проблемно
Well, its not that its rotting, its
Да ну она не то что загнивает она
still, lets say, I havent heard of it, its in
всё-таки вот скажем не слышал она на
tenth
десятом
place among countries Where is the best place to live on
месте по странам Где лучше всего жить на
earth, after all Yes, its not a bad place to
земле всё-таки Да неплохое место для
exist But this is a different culture
существования Но это же Другая культура
You understand, there are still clans
Вы же поймите там вот до сих пор кланы
there, if you quit your job, Ill
там вот если ты с работы уволился гую
work with you Why are you  quit you and they won't
рабо с А почему ты уволился тебя и не
take you they'll say you're such a person quit, it
возьмут скажут ты человек такой уволился
means they don't
значит тебе не
trust you, it's a bit of a
доверяют это немножко
la, I understand, it's clear with that, yes, let's
такая ла понял с этим понятно да давайте
take
так возьмём Британия Какие сейчас
Britain, what are the
проблемы За что жалеем Британию что там
problems
у неё за проблемы
now? Why do we feel sorry for Britain, what are its problems now? Well, Britain has been
теперь Ну Британия последнее врем
buying oil with the Netherlands lately, they
прох покупали нефть с нидерландами у них
had this, the Netherlands, they banned oil
было это Нидерланды что-то запретили
production now because
сейчас вырабатывать нефть из-за того что
they have, damn,
у них
what kind of
там блин какие там
natural problems, I'm
природные природные проблемы немножко
not expressing myself that way. Well, in general,
сес не так выражаюсь Ну в общем первая
their first problem is energy. They're
проблема у них Энергетическая
still solving it. The second problem is
пока решают вторая проблема
demographics, because lately
демография потому что последнее время у
they've had more and more
них больше и больше с
immigrants, the name, say, Muhammad, is more
эмигрантами имя скажем Мухаммед более
common than, say,
часто встречается чем скажем
John, so far it's been with them for years. I
Джон пока это у них в течение лет Я
think in 5-7 years it won't matter, but I think
думаю 5-7 не будет важно но думаю лет
in
через
15 years Britain will have little influence. Do I
15 Британия будет мало чего влиять с я
understand correctly that you live in Russia,
правильно понимаю что вы живя в России
where there are a lot of Tajiks, Chechens,
где э немерено там таджиков чеченцев
Dagestanis now. Where in Tyumen is the most
сейчас дагестанцев Где в Тюмени самое
common name
распространённое имя
Muhammad among newborns? You
Мухамад среди новорожденных вы
say that in Britain there  something
рассказываете что в Британии там что-то
there too names in short yes And
там тоже имена короче да А
you don't know did you ever live in Russia No
вы не знаю вы в России когда-то жили Нет
thank
слава
God In vain you so I had a friend
Богу Зря вы так вот у меня друг был
Muhammad in the army I had a friend Muhammad
Мухамед в армии У меня друг был Мухамед
Mukhamedovich England I say mu we
мухамедович Англии я му говорю мы с ними
live next to them you see this is a slightly
живём рядом это видиш это немножко
different situation We live next to them we are
разная ситуация Мы с ними рядом живём мы
friends with them we have no problems
с ними дружим у нас проблем
even with the Tajiks I understand
нет даже с таджиками понял
so work
так работат
houses built no problems But let's
дома строили никаких проблем нету А вот
say uh take if the same England there are
скажем э брать если ту же Англию там с
big problems with this there are no such as
этом большие проблемы там же э нету так
with us I want to say all the time the
как как у нас Я хочу всё время сказать
Soviet Union Because I love the
Советский Союз Потому что я люблю
Soviet Union in my idea not how it
Советский Союз по своей идее ни как он
was organized but the idea itself I really
был организован но сама Идея мне очень
like the idea
нравится ка идея
Understand the idea of equality of all so that every
Поня идея равенства всех чтобы каждый
person from school could apply even
человек со школы мог претендовать даже
for the highest authorities so that he had the
на высшие органы чтобы он у него было
right to education for free medicine
право на обучение на бесплатную медицину
for all this so that he could become anyone
на всё это чтобы он мог стать кем угодно
Any person this idea I really
Любой человек вот эта идея Мне очень
like and let's say in the same in the same
нравится а скажем в той же в той же
England we have in
Англии
ro wounds such areas such wounds such And with
ро раны таких районы таких раны таких А
us all the people live  here in my building
у нас все люди живут вот в моём подъезде
live people from Georgia
живут и люди из Грузии
and yes, everyone
И всё
from Georgia but around I see a lot of
да из Грузии но вокруг Я вижу много тоже
people of different nationalities they are not mixed up in
людей разные национально они Т перемешку
clans like the nerd way of life in America Yes there is
не кланами как неры быт в Америке Да
such a district there are only blacks
есть район такой там одни только чёрные
living there there is RAO they are there even NH
живут есть РАО такие они там вот даже нч
there are like Russians living there I don't know maybe it is like that
там как бы русские живут Я не знаю может
but now in Russia we all live
есть но сейчас у нас в России живут все
mixed up it turns out let's do it England
перемет получается давай так Англии
now has more problems than Russia
сейчас проблем больше чем в России
so yeah Well what's up Well the rich are unlikely to have
так да Ну каки там Ну у богатых вряд ли
more the poor yes they have
про больше у бедных да у них сечас
become a little more expensive now Well ours has become more
подорожало немножко Ну у нас больше
expensive Well no wait that's not to say it that way
подорожало Ну нет подожди не так сказать
uh the problem Honestly everyone in
ээ проблема Честно говоря у всех и в
Europe and Russia has problems this is this
Европе и у России проблем это вот это
honestly speaking 50 to 50 Everyone has problems
честно говоря 50 на 50 У всех проблемы
but how will we get out of these problems
есть а вот как мы выйдем из этих проблем
who will find it easier let's say in five years this
кому легче будет скажем лет через пять
I don't know so I understood okay E
вот это я не знаю так понял хорошо Э
come on so uh where shall we
давай так ээ где
tell people Where is the standard of living higher for
людям скажем Где выше уровень жизни у
people in Britain or in Russia the
людей в Британии или в России
standard of living is not an indicator
уровень жизни - это же не показатель
just where is the higher standard of living in
просто где вышей уровень жизни в
Britain or in
Британии или в
Russia I can't damn it I wasn't there
России не могу те блин я же не был
never in Britain I but in my opinion
никогда в Британии я но по моему мнению
in my opinion Yes the standard of living That is,
по моему мнению Да уровень жизни То есть
as a standard of
как уровень
living it is easier to get money It seems to me
жизни легче деньги достаются Мне кажется
in Britain it is easier to get money in
в Британии легче деньги достаются в
Britain
Британии
but where is it better to live is a question I do not
а вот жить Где лучше это вопрос я не
know this is another real question
знаю это другой реальный вопрос
firstly We have
во-первых У нас
real education here and preschool everything is
тут реально образование и дошкольном всё
free and medicine is basically not bad I
бесплатно и медицина в принципе неплохая
see yes in medicine Well in medicine we
я вижу да по медицине Ну по медицине мы
see you are fine so far
видим вы прекрасно пока что медицина
medicine is not bad access no choice I say so this is medicine they
говорю так это медицина мне
can give me Listen well and do you have free medicine let's say in the
могут Слушай ну а у вас как бы есть
same
бесплатная медицина вот скажем в той же
in the same Great Britain there is
в той же Великобритании там ездит
free medicine there you have to
бесплатная медицина там надо очереди
wait in line yes but there for some reason in Russia I
ждать да но там почему-то вот в России я
go to the Roulette and here Every third person is
выхожу в щт Рулетку и тут Каждый третий
toothless in Britain everyone has teeth I don't
без зубов в Британии все с зубами Я не
know what kind of medicine there is but everyone has
знаю какая там медицина но там все с
teeth everyone my
зубами все
wife doesn't have a single tooth they are white
у меня у жены ни одного зуба не они
pretty Yes but this is my
беленький красивенький Да но это моя
wife she is a beauty Yes she has everything and
жена она красавица Да у неё всё есть а у
I do And I have it like this I am saying I am saying there are
меня А у меня вот так вот Я вот говорю Я
Men who are like Sambi  They
говорю есть Мужики которые вот Самби ими
buy clothes for themselves there And for
там ну себе одежду покупают А я вот
example, I took a boat and went to Kama and
например взял лодку поехал на Каму и
fished
рыбачу
Ira I go fishing on the weekend And that's how it is
Ир я прохожу на выходные на рыбалку И
in life And can you listen for the
вот так вот в жизни А можешь вот слушай
sake of interest you can I have never seen
ради интереса можешь Я никогда не видел
how Russians have apartments furnished can you
как у Россиян квартиры обст можешь
show me because I have
показать потому что я английские
seen English apartments Can you show me Yes, a
квартиры видел Можешь показать Да
small excursion I want to
экскурсию да такую небольшую хочу
evaluate how and so well
оценить как
yes just Twist Yes Twist like this Oh
а так ну да просто Покрути Да Покрути
by the way here is a picture Here you see a picture Yes yes this is
так О кстати вот рисунок Вот видишь
my 8 year old daughter
рисунок Да да это моя дочка 8ми лет
drew a dragon she says Dad is it you I
нарисовала дракона говорит Папа это ты Я
say I am a worm or something you
говорю Я Червяк что ли
see the picture Well how a little Show me more
видишь карти Ну как немножко Покажи
furnishings
обстановочка
Wow how much you read Well done this is
Ого ско кни много читаешь Молодец это
not enough Here are some more books for me There is
мало Вот вот тут мне ещё вот книги Тут
still a lot to put here And what kind of
ещё много некуда укладывать А что за
books What kind of books are you reading Show me oh
книги Что за книги читаешь Покажи
books we will
ой книги муке
not know the secret of flour where else it is bad to live besides
не узнаем тайну где ещё плохо жить кроме
Britain eh-eh-eh It's a pity In short you
Британии эх-эх-эх Жаль Короче вы
understand sits in
поняли сидит в
Russia without a
России без
man But what is there remember what Azarov said 11 years
челю Но что там помни что Азаров 11 лет
ago  in e vez there are problems
назад говорил в е в ез там проблемы
sour cream kefir there is not even such a thing well
сметана кефиры там же даже такого нет ну
you only yoghurts Yes in Britain there are
ты же только йогурты Да в Британии там
such problems in Japan such
то такие проблемы в Японии такие
Britain in short there Denmark Netherlands
Британия короче там Дания Нидерланды
something sells oil in short they
что-то там продают нефть Короче они всё
know everything about everyone What where in what countries
знают про всех Какие где В каких странах
problems But in Russia it is
проблемы Но в России
good He sits without a heart
хорошо Он сидит без люхи
and worries about other countries
и переживает о других странах Как
I feel
европейцев мне
sorry for the Europeans I feel sorry for the Europeans because gas
жалко европейцев жалко потому что газ
They refused gas everything next
Они отказались от газа всё в следующем
year they will
году они уже
freeze they are sitting in poverty they are sitting
замёрзнут они сидят в нищете они сидят
in such medical conditions simply
в таких условиях медицинских просто
terrible and instead of thinking how to
ужасных и вместо того чтобы думать как
improve their lives They think How is
улучшить свою жизнь Они думают Как там
something there Damn in Europe like squeak comment
чтото Блин в Европе лайк писка комент
write on y instag I dont know why it is for
пись на й instag Я не знаю для чого це
you to look at your
тоб для чого тоб там дивитись на оцей
face and for you it is one two or three
фейс а для тебе це один два або три
clicks Ale ti trimae me and I will show
клика Але ти тримае мене и я буду казати
you in me there are a bunch of fouls and in me there will be a
ва в мене там Купа фолов и в мене буде
cool mood  robiti Novy kru Vio pis
класний настр щоб робити Нови кру Вио
nay instr pok Andriy so
пись най instr пок Андрий так
Come on I'm waiting for you
Давай я тебя чекаю